Daniel!
다니엘!
Mother!
어머니!
- When did you arrive? - I arrived yesterday.
- 언제 도착했어요? - 어제 도착했어요.
So long.
그럼 또.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
I've heard a lot about you.
나는 당신에 대해 많이 들었습니다.
For Daniel, of course.
물론 다니엘에게도요.
Oh really?
오, 진짜?
Every time I talked about you, I wondered.
당신에 대해 이야기할 때마다 나는 궁금했어요.
About me?
나에 대해?
I was curious about you.
나는 당신이 궁금했습니다.
How would you be, how would you look.
당신은 어떨지, 어떤 모습일지.
But you...
하지만 당신은...
you have dignity.
당신은 위엄이 있습니다.
That is,
즉,
You are more impressive than I imagined.
당신은 내가 상상했던 것보다 더 인상적이군요.
When I say "awesome", It's a compliment, right?
내가 "대단하다"고 말하면, 칭찬이죠?
Yes.
예.
Daniel!
다니엘!
Hello, Daniel.
안녕, 다니엘.
You were amazing today.
오늘 정말 대단했어요.
- Hello.
- 안녕하세요.
- I'm Ji Min's mom. - Hello, you must be Ji Min.
- 저는 지민 엄마예요. - 안녕하세요, 지민이시군요.
You were wonderful, you did a great job.
당신은 정말 훌륭했고, 훌륭한 일을 해냈습니다.
I always thought Daniel was handsome,
나는 항상 다니엘이 잘생겼다고 생각했는데,
and now I see that it runs in the family.
이제 나는 그것이 가족 내에서 운영되는 것을 봅니다.
- Hello. - I'm glad to see you.
- 안녕하세요. - 만나서 반가워요.
Jun Kyung.
준경.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
Why are you apologizing?
왜 사과하는 거야?
I didn't expect it to appear like this.
이런 모습이 나올 거라고는 예상하지 못했습니다.
Of course yes,
물론이죠.
She is Daniel's mother.
그녀는 다니엘의 어머니입니다.
-Do Hyun. - Yeah?
-도현. - 응?
You should see Daniel's teacher.
다니엘 선생님을 만나야 해요.
I already greeted her.
나는 이미 그녀에게 인사를 했습니다.
Wait a second, don't leave yet.
잠깐만요, 아직 떠나지 마세요.
Why are you so nervous?
왜 그렇게 긴장해요?
Wouldn't it be?
그렇지 않습니까?
Because?
왜냐하면?
For me?
나를 위한?
Hey, everyone here looks uncomfortable except...
저기, 여기 있는 사람들 다 불편해 보이는데...
My name is Im Yun Ju.
제 이름은 임윤주입니다.
...except you.
...당신만 빼고요.
Does that amuse you?
그게 재미있나요?
Let's have dinner together.
같이 저녁 먹자.
You came all this way to see Daniel play.
다니엘이 플레이하는 모습을 보기 위해 여기까지 오셨는데요.
Yes, I'm going out.
응, 나갈 거야.
You can start without me.
나 없이도 시작할 수 있습니다.
It's okay, I'm sorry.
괜찮아요, 미안해요.
Even if it's late, finish before you leave.
늦더라도 떠나기 전에 끝내세요.
Understood.
이해했다.
TRUE.
진실.
Regarding field practice of the second years...
현장실습에 관해서 2학년 중...
Wait.
잠깐만요.
You know the password to my computer, right?
내 컴퓨터의 비밀번호를 알고 계시죠?
- But I'm in the middle of this... - This is more urgent.
- 그런데 난 이 와중에... - 이게 더 급해요.
If you are hungry, order something.
배가 고프면 뭔가를 주문하세요.
OK.
좋아요.
- Make the notification first. - Yes sir.
- 먼저 알림을 받으세요. - 네, 선생님.
- Hello. - Finally
- 안녕하세요. - 드디어
I pressed the button!
버튼을 눌렀어요!
What button?
무슨 버튼?
What a cold response
정말 차가운 반응이네요
at the beginning of your girlfriend's trip to become a successful writer.
여자친구 여행 초반에 성공적인 작가가 되기 위해.
I told you, today was the deadline.
내가 말했잖아, 오늘이 마감일이라고.
I delivered it!
배달했어요!
Clear!
분명한!
How about a pork chop and a beer?
돼지갈비와 맥주 한잔 어때요?
We could celebrate together.
우리는 함께 축하할 수 있었습니다.
Okay, I'll finish as soon as possible.
알겠습니다. 최대한 빨리 마치겠습니다.
See you later.
나중에 봐요.
Come in, please.
들어오세요.
Isn't the teacher here?
선생님은 여기 안 계시나요?
It's already gone.
이미 사라졌습니다.
Because?
왜냐하면?
Well...
잘...
Can I hand this in now?
지금 이걸 제출해도 될까요?
- You should have done it before. - I'm sorry.
- 진작에 했어야 했는데. - 죄송합니다.
And this too.
그리고 이것도.
- Thank you. - Bye bye.
- 감사합니다. - 안녕.
Bye bye.
안녕.
- Here you go. - Thank you.
- 여기요. - 감사합니다.
It's still very clean.
아직은 매우 깨끗합니다.
I almost feel bad taking it.
나는 그것을 받아들이는 것이 거의 기분이 좋지 않습니다.
I'm glad they put it to good use.
유용하게 사용하게 되어 기쁘네요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
- I will take good care of her. - Thank you.
- 내가 그 사람을 잘 돌볼게요. - 감사합니다.
Live well in that nice house.
그 좋은 집에서 잘 살아요.
Ja Yeong,
자영,
are you okay?
괜찮아?
Now it is an empty house, only memories remain.
지금은 빈집이 되어 추억만 남아있습니다.
I don't care anymore.
더 이상 상관하지 않습니다.
Let's eat something delicious.
맛있는 것을 먹자.
What do you want?
당신은 무엇을 원하세요?
Whatever you want.
당신이 원하는 무엇이든.
Well, what I want is...
뭐, 내가 원하는 건...
Is this what you wanted?
이것이 당신이 원했던 것입니까?
They say the best food in the world
세상에서 가장 맛있는 음식이라고 하던데
the ramen that someone prepares for you
누군가가 당신을 위해 준비한 라면
open sky.
열린 하늘.
I guess you're right.
당신 말이 맞는 것 같아요.
Eat the ramen you made with you
너랑 만든 라면 먹어
It tastes better than noodles in the Alps.
알프스 국수보다 맛이 좋아요.
I didn't do it, it was the machine.
내가 한 게 아니라 기계였어.
Be careful, it's leaking.
조심하세요, 새고 있어요.
Still don't feel like working?
아직도 일할 기분이 아니신가요?
Yes.
예.
When Bom got sick,
봄이가 아팠을 때,
I took a break from work to be by his side a little more.
일을 쉬었어요 조금 더 그의 곁에 있기 위해.
It's been six months now.
이제 6개월이 지났습니다.
Yes, time flies.
네, 시간이 빨리 가네요.
Those birds...
그 새들...
They fly freely wherever they want,
그들은 원하는 곳 어디든 자유롭게 날아다닌다.
But when they get old and tired,
그러나 그들이 늙고 피곤해지면,
and they can no longer fly away,
그리고 그들은 더 이상 날아갈 수 없습니다.
what's happening?
무슨 일이야?
Does it
그렇습니까?
They end up settling somewhere, becoming resident birds?
그들은 결국 어딘가에 정착하게 되고, 텃새가 되다?
Maybe.
아마도.
I had never thought about it.
나는 그것에 대해 생각해 본 적이 없습니다.
It's a little sad.
조금 슬프다.
I think it's fine.
내 생각엔 괜찮을 것 같아.
They have spent their entire lives chasing good seasons.
그들은 평생을 보냈습니다. 좋은 계절을 쫓아.
A place where you are the first to see the flowers open,
당신이 처음인 곳 꽃이 활짝 피는 모습을 보고,
to feel the sun on your skin,
피부에 닿는 태양을 느끼기 위해,
in stepping on fallen leaves,
낙엽을 밟으면서
to see the snow melt.
눈이 녹는 것을 보려고.
If there is such a place,
그런 곳이 있다면,
be a resident bird,
텃새가 되어라,
that stays in one place, receives and dismisses people,
한 곳에 머무르는 것, 사람을 받아들이고 내보내고,
It would be nice.
좋을 것입니다.
I have lived my entire life as a migratory bird.
나는 평생을 철새로 살아왔습니다.
Who says the pork chop Does it go well with beer?
누가 돼지갈비라고 했나 맥주랑 잘 어울리나요?
That's poor people consoling themselves.
그것은 가난한 사람들이 스스로를 위로하는 것입니다.
The pork chop goes with whiskey.
돼지갈비는 위스키와 잘 어울린다.
At least 30 years.
최소 30년.
What's happening?
무슨 일이야?
Your face doesn't say "party."
당신의 얼굴은 "파티"라고 말하지 않습니다.
While everyone improved their averages and built careers,
모두가 평균을 향상시키는 동안 그리고 경력을 쌓았고,
what was I doing?
내가 뭘 하고 있었지?
you were very busy falling in love and dating.
당신은 매우 바빴어요 사랑에 빠지고 데이트를 합니다.
I sent you my manuscript
나는 당신에게 내 원고를 보냈습니다
thinking you would be perfect as a critic of romantic novels,
당신이 완벽할 것이라고 생각 로맨스 소설 평론가로서
and you didn't even finish it,
그리고 넌 그걸 끝내지도 않았어
right?
그렇죠?
I'm sorry,
미안해요
but I know it will work.
하지만 나는 그것이 효과가 있을 것이라는 것을 안다.
Of course!
물론!
Do you remember the plan
계획을 기억하시나요?
What did I do when I joined the publishing house?
출판사에 입사하면서 나는 무엇을 했나요?
after I graduate, right?
내가 졸업하고 나면, 그렇지?
I would save 24 million won
2400만원 아껴야지
to write until I turned 30.
30살이 될 때까지 글을 쓰려고요.
Then I would quit my job.
그러면 나는 직장을 그만둘 것이다.
and I would enter the contest
그리고 나는 대회에 참가할 것이다
in the spring of my 29th birthday.
내 29번째 생일의 봄.
And when the results came out in three months,
그리고 3개월 뒤에 결과가 나왔을 때,
I would publish my book
나는 내 책을 출판할 것이다
before turning 30.
30세가 되기 전에.
Just as I planned.
내가 계획한 대로요.
Have you finished drinking yet?
벌써 술 다 마셨나요?
It's too early to drink just for entering the contest.
술을 마시기엔 아직 이르다 단지 대회에 참가하기 위해서다.
Something very good is coming soon.
아주 좋은 일이 곧 올 것입니다.
That day is when I will finish this bottle.
그날은 내가 이 병을 다 비울 날이다.
Do you really think
정말 그렇게 생각하시나요?
that life is going as you planned?
인생은 당신이 계획한 대로 흘러가고 있나요?
Why are you always so pessimistic?
왜 항상 그렇게 비관적입니까?
Why are you always so optimistic?
당신은 왜 항상 그렇게 낙관적인가요?
I am not
나는 아니다
neither pessimistic nor optimistic.
비관적이지도 낙관적이지도 않다.
I am idealistic.
나는 이상주의자이다.
If that woman had been a little more educated,
그 여자가 좀 더 교육을 받았더라면,
or if he didn't look younger than me,
아니면 그 사람이 나보다 어려 보이지 않았다면
or if she wasn't so pretty...
아니면 너무 예쁘지 않았다면...
Would I feel that way anyway?
그래도 나도 그런 기분이 들까?
Did you know?
알고 계셨나요?
He told you: "Dinner with your family."
그는 당신에게 "가족과 함께 저녁 식사"라고 말했습니다.
That was too much.
너무 과했어요.
It was the worst, wasn't it?
최악이었지, 그렇지?
It's understandable.
이해할 수 있습니다.
Your current boyfriend's ex,
현재 남자친구의 전 남친,
his son, all four of them there.
그의 아들, 네 명 모두 거기에 있습니다.
Anyone would go crazy.
누구라도 미칠 것입니다.
They seemed like the perfect family,
완벽한 가족 같았지만,
and I am a villain without an invitation that appeared on the scene.
그리고 나는 초대받지 않은 악당이다 현장에 나타난 것입니다.
I completely understand that feeling.
나는 그 느낌을 완전히 이해합니다.
Every time I go to meetings
모임에 갈 때마다
from my in-laws, uncles, aunts, cousins,
내 친척, 삼촌, 숙모, 사촌,
everyone is strangely happy
다들 이상하게 행복해
and I'm the only stranger involved in his family.
그리고 나는 그의 가족과 관련된 유일한 낯선 사람입니다.
My husband tries a lot
남편이 노력을 많이 해요
to understand the situation, stuck in the middle.
상황을 이해하기 위해, 중간에 붙어있습니다.
Don't you realize Does that make me like him less?
당신은 깨닫지 못합니까? 그러면 내가 그 사람을 덜 좋아하게 되는 걸까?
Children, daddy has arrived!
얘들아, 아빠가 왔다!
- Daddy! - Daddy.
- 아빠! - 아빠.
Were they having fun?
그들은 재미있었나요?
What is this?
이게 뭔가요?
He really doesn't know.
그는 정말로 모른다.
Jun Kyung, when did you arrive?
준경 씨, 언제 도착했어요?
When did you arrive?
언제 도착하셨나요?
I was very bored at the hospital today. You came to save me.
오늘 병원에 있어서 너무 지루했어요. 당신은 나를 구하러 오셨습니다.
What happened?
무슨 일이에요?
They didn't go very far without me, did they?
나 없이는 별로 멀리 가지 못했지, 그렇지?
What's happening?
무슨 일이야?
Is it serious?
심각한가요?
Is it a serious situation?
심각한 상황인가요?
Wait. I will give you the best advice in the world.
기다리다. 나는 당신에게 세상 최고의 조언을 해줄 것입니다.
Let me change quickly.
빨리 바꾸게 해주세요.
Don't go.
가지 마세요.
Eat pizza too.
피자도 먹고.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
It looks delicious.
맛있어 보이네요.
Do you want a glass of wine?
와인 한 잔 드릴까요?
I'm fine.
잘 지내요.
If you want, go ahead.
원한다면 계속하세요.
I stopped drinking.
나는 술을 끊었습니다.
By the way,
그건 그렇고,
Shouldn't you come next week?
다음주에 오면 안되나요?
I came before.
나는 전에 왔습니다.
I also wanted to see Daniel's recital.
다니엘의 연주회도 보고 싶었어요.
You should have warned us.
우리에게 경고했어야 했는데.
I wanted to surprise them.
나는 그들을 놀라게 하고 싶었다.
Yes, it was a total surprise.
네, 정말 놀랐습니다.
Right?
오른쪽?
I saw everything from the beginning.
나는 처음부터 모든 것을 보았습니다.
- From the beginning? - Yes.
- 처음부터요? - 예.
You were incredible.
당신은 정말 대단했어요.
Birth rates fell, so I walk on eggshells.
출산율이 떨어졌고, 그래서 나는 달걀 껍질 위를 걷는다.
There are more and more psychiatric patients and everyone asks for Hyeong Jun.
정신과 환자가 점점 많아지고 있어요 그리고 다들 형준을 요구해요.
I thought things would calm down
상황이 진정될 줄 알았는데
Now that the children are older, So I gave everything with confidence,
이제 아이들도 좀 컸으니, 그래서 나는 모든 것을 자신 있게 바쳤고,
but the only thing that grew
하지만 유일하게 자란 것은
It was my knowledge to make liquor
술을 만드는 것은 나의 지식이었다
and my abdominal fat.
그리고 내 뱃살.
And I don't even have anything to wear for Dr. Hong's wedding.
그리고 입을 옷도 없어요 홍박사님의 결혼식을 위해.
And it's not that I have "nothing good to wear",
그리고 '입을 만한 좋은 옷이 없다'는 것이 아니라,
This time I have nothing at all.
이번에는 아무것도 없습니다.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
That's not comforting, is it?
그건 위로가 되지 않죠, 그렇죠?
No.
아니요.
I don't know why, but this spring
왜인지는 모르겠지만 이번 봄에는
It feels especially bitter.
특히 씁쓸한 느낌이 듭니다.
As if it was going to be very cruel.
마치 매우 잔인할 것처럼요.
The children finally fell asleep.
아이들은 마침내 잠들었습니다.
What's happening? What's the real mess?
무슨 일이야? 진짜 혼란은 무엇입니까?
Gosh, the alcohol is over.
맙소사, 술은 끝났다.
Wait, don't start yet.
잠깐, 아직 시작하지 마세요.
Why Do Hyun
도현이 왜?
hasn't he called you?
그 사람이 너한테 전화하지 않았어?
Thank you
감사합니다
for taking care of Daniel.
다니엘을 돌봐줘서.
It's nothing,
아무것도 아니야
It's what I should do.
그게 내가 해야 할 일이야.
Of course yes,
물론이죠.
you are his father.
당신은 그의 아버지입니다.
You're moving out this month, right?
이번 달에 이사가는 거 맞지?
Yes.
예.
It's pretty. I mean, Jun Kyung.
예쁘네요. 내 말은, 준경아.
Still charming, I guess.
여전히 매력적인 것 같아요.
Did you find a place?
장소는 찾았나요?
Do you change the subject?
주제를 바꾸나요?
I'll stay at my mom's house for now.
나는 당분간 엄마 집에 머물 예정이다.
He's in Canada, visiting my brother.
그는 내 동생을 방문하기 위해 캐나다에 있습니다.
I didn't expect a warm welcome,
따뜻한 환영을 기대하진 않았지만,
but you are exactly the same.
하지만 당신은 똑같습니다.
That look on your face
네 얼굴에 그 표정
It's exactly how you looked when I left Korea 16 years ago.
바로 당신의 모습이었습니다 16년 전 한국을 떠났을 때.
You know,
아시다시피,
an ordinary day,
평범한 하루,
I'm on the bus
나는 버스에 있어요
and someone is reading my book.
누군가가 내 책을 읽고 있어요.
- Yes. - And then,
- 예. - 그러다가,
I see that they read it.
나는 그들이 그것을 읽는 것을 봅니다.
Don't you feel like your heart is going to explode?
심장이 터질 것 같지 않으세요?
You don't want to be a big famous author.
당신은 유명하고 유명한 작가가 되고 싶지 않습니다.
You don't need to write a best seller or earn a lot of money.
베스트 셀러를 쓸 필요는 없습니다. 아니면 돈을 많이 벌거나.
Do you only have that small dream?
그 작은 꿈만 가지고 있나요?
Although the pessimist I kept showing him the cold reality,
비관주의자이긴 하지만 차가운 현실을 계속 보여줬는데
The idealist, strangely, felt at peace,
이상주의자는 이상하게도 마음이 편해졌다.
and the drinks tasted sweet.
그리고 음료는 달콤한 맛이 났어요.
- Bye bye.
- 안녕.
- You first.
- 당신이 먼저요.
- Leave. - OK.
- 떠나다. - 좋아요.
- Bye bye.
- 안녕.
Do you want me to accompany you?
내가 당신과 동행하길 원하시나요?
Yes.
예.
Let's go.
갑시다.
Will you accompany me again?
또 나랑 같이 가줄래?
I'm already getting tired.
나는 벌써 피곤해지고 있다.
That? I'll be bored alone.
저것? 혼자 심심할 것 같아요.
No?
아니요?
So, stay at my house.
그러니 내 집에 머물러라.
Ought?
영?
Aren't you hungry?
배고프지 않나요?
A place where you are the first to see the flowers open,
당신이 처음인 곳 꽃이 활짝 피는 모습을 보고
in feeling the sun on the skin,
피부에 닿는 태양을 느끼면서
in stepping on fallen leaves,
낙엽을 밟으며
in watching the snow melt.
눈이 녹는 것을 지켜보는 중
If there is such a place,
그런 곳이 있다면
be a resident bird,
상주하는 새가 되어보세요
that stays in one place, receives and dismisses people,
한 곳에 머물며 사람들을 받아들이고 해고합니다.
it would be nice.
좋겠네요.
I have lived my entire life as a migratory bird.
나는 평생을 철새로 살아왔습니다.
Dad, I'm not going home tonight.
아빠, 오늘 밤에는 집에 안 갈 거예요.
Don't wait up for me.
나를 기다리지 마세요.
Now it's an empty house,
지금은 빈 집이지만
only memories remain.
추억만 남습니다.
I don't mind.
나는 상관하지 않는다.
That look on your face...
저 표정...
it's exactly how you looked when I left Korea 16 years ago.
바로 당신 모습이에요 16년 전 한국을 떠났을 때
It seems like it will be warm forever,
영원히 따뜻할 것 같네요,
until, suddenly,
갑자기
that look appears,
그 모습이 나타납니다
as if to say: "I'm exhausted."
마치 "나는 지쳤어요."라고 말하는 것처럼
That's the look he makes
그 사람의 표정은 이렇습니다
someone leave.
누군가 떠나세요.
[Missed call: Do Hyun]
[부재중 전화 : 도현]
Do you know the difference between loneliness and isolation?
차이점을 아시나요? 외로움과 고립 사이?
Solitude is the joy of choosing to be alone.
고독은 혼자 있기를 선택하는 기쁨입니다.
Isolation is pain of being alone against your will.
고립은 고통이다 당신의 의지에 반하여 혼자 있는 것.
So, now,
자, 이제
what do you feel?
기분이 어때요?
Loneliness
외로움
or isolation?
또는 격리?
Wow.
와우.
Just in time.
제때에.
I also wanted a beer.
나도 맥주를 마시고 싶었다.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
Why do you have to apologize?
왜 사과해야 합니까?
I am...
나는...
the one who should apologize.
사과해야 할 사람.
I'm very tired today.
오늘은 매우 피곤해요.
I'm going in.
나는 들어갈 것이다.
You said I didn't do anything wrong...
내가 잘못한 게 없다고 했잖아...
But you treat me like I did it.
하지만 당신은 내가 그랬던 것처럼 나를 대합니다.
Clear. Why do you make me feel this way?
분명한. 왜 나한테 이런 기분이 들게 만드는 걸까?
I know you have a son,
당신에게 아들이 있는 것으로 알고 있어요.
I knew that Yun Ju would return,
윤주가 돌아올 줄 알았어
but when we were standing there the three together,
하지만 우리가 거기 서 있었을 때 셋이 함께,
I was the only one who looked stupid.
멍청해 보이는 사람은 나뿐이었다.
I know that nobody did anything wrong,
누구도 잘못한 게 없다는 걸 알아요
But I hate myself for feeling this way.
하지만 나는 이런 생각을 하는 내 자신이 싫다.
I feel pathetic and childish.
한심하고 유치한 느낌이 듭니다.
I hate this.
나는 이것을 싫어한다.
See?
보다?
I'm the one who's wrong.
내가 틀렸어.
You've always been like this,
당신은 늘 이런 식이었어요.
the two years we have been together.
우리가 함께한 2년.
When things get like this...
상황이 이렇게 되면...
you walk away first.
당신이 먼저 떠나세요.
You run.
당신은 달린다.
You hide.
당신은 숨는다.
Therefore, I ask your forgiveness...
그러므로 양해를 구합니다...
for making you feel this way
당신이 이런 느낌을 갖게 해주셔서
again.
다시.
- Welcome. - Hello.
- 환영. - 안녕하세요.
- Beautiful mountains, right? - Yes.
- 아름다운 산이죠? - 예.
Over here.
여기요.
This is the kitchen area.
이곳은 주방 공간입니다.
Good cold water pressure.
냉수 수압 좋음.
Since it is small,
규모가 작기 때문에,
There is not much to maintain.
유지할 것이 많지 않습니다.
This is the office and the store.
여기는 사무실이자 매장이에요.
We have everything.
우리는 모든 것을 갖추고 있습니다.
Take a look.
보세요.
and here it is
그리고 여기 있어요
where we live
우리가 사는 곳
my partner and I.
내 파트너와 나.
Please come.
꼭 오세요.
I thought that only
그것만 생각했는데
you had come to camp.
당신은 캠프에 왔었습니다.
I had no idea what you thought
나는 당신이 어떻게 생각하는지 전혀 몰랐어요
buy the place.
그 곳을 사세요.
I thought I'd try camping first,
캠핑을 먼저 해보자고 생각했는데,
but plans never go well.
하지만 계획은 결코 잘 진행되지 않습니다.
Seeing this place,
이 곳을 보니,
I feel like I would regret it if I let it go.
놔두면 후회할 것 같아요.
You're sure?
확실해요?
Is it really okay?
정말 괜찮나요?
What do you think?
어떻게 생각하나요?
For me, it's okay, I'm alone,
나에겐 괜찮아, 난 혼자니까
but you
하지만 당신은
you have children.
당신에게는 자녀가 있습니다.
The anniversary is approaching of my wife's death.
기념일이 다가오고 있어요 내 아내의 죽음.
Do you know what I regret the most?
내가 가장 후회하는 것이 무엇인지 아시나요?
after losing her?
그녀를 잃은 후?
I should have retired earlier.
더 일찍 은퇴했어야 했는데.
I should have spent more time with her.
나는 그녀와 더 많은 시간을 보냈어야 했어요.
I already decided.
나는 이미 결정했다.
She would have wanted him to live like this.
그녀는 그가 이렇게 살기를 바랐을 것이다.
and the children
그리고 아이들
they will understand.
그들은 이해할 것이다.
Hey, Jun Seo.
안녕하세요, 서준님.
Dad,
아빠,
I think I'll be late again.
또 늦을 것 같아.
Are you at home?
집에 있나요?
No, I went out too.
아니, 나도 나갔어.
Where are you?
당신은 어디에 있나요?
Camping with Ja Yeong.
자영과 함께하는 캠핑.
Sounds great, have fun with it.
좋네요. 재미있게 즐겨보세요.
Don't stay at home all the time.
항상 집에 있지 마세요.
Jun Seo.
서준.
By the way, did I tell you...?
그런데 내가 말했지...?
Did I give you your allowance?
내가 당신에게 용돈을 주었나요?
Yes, I still have it, you gave it to me last week.
네, 아직도 갖고 있어요. 지난주에 주셨거든요.
Don't worry about me. Have fun, okay?
나에 대해서는 걱정하지 마세요. 재미있게 보내세요, 그렇죠?
Okay.
알았어.
They will understand.
그들은 이해할 것입니다.
Is the house in your name?
그 집이 당신 이름인가요?
Yes.
예.
Did your children help you financially? when did you buy it?
자녀가 재정적으로 도움을 주었나요? 언제 샀어?
No.
아니요.
So what's the problem?
그렇다면 문제는 무엇입니까?
It's your house, you just want to sell it.
그것은 당신의 집입니다. 당신은 그것을 팔고 싶습니다.
I wonder
궁금해요
yes I'm being selfish and I only pursue my own happiness.
응, 난 이기적이야 나는 오직 나만의 행복만을 추구합니다.
Even sins of the heart are sins, right?
마음의 죄도 죄이겠죠?
All humans are selfish.
인간은 모두 이기적이다.
That's what I'm saying, maybe I'm too selfish.
내 말은, 어쩌면 내가 너무 이기적인 것일지도 모른다.
So, don't sell the house. Please.
그러니 집은 팔지 마세요. 제발.
Hey, Chang Sik.
안녕하세요, 창식님.
My life matters too, right?
내 인생도 중요하잖아요?
Listen,
들어봐,
Yesterday another man came to confess.
어제 또 다른 남자가 자백하러 왔습니다.
He said he heard an important piece of information and asked if he should buy shares.
중요한 정보를 들었다고 하더군요 그리고 주식을 사야하는지 물었습니다.
He said his wife would kill him if she found out.
아내가 알면 죽이겠다고 하더군요.
Do you know what I told him?
내가 그에게 무슨 말을 했는지 아세요?
Don't know.
모르겠어요.
I told him:
나는 그에게 이렇게 말했습니다.
"Go home right now and talk to her before she finds out.
"당장 집에 가세요 그리고 그녀가 알기 전에 얘기해 보세요.
And if you make a lot of money,
그리고 돈을 많이 벌면
"Donate more to the church."
"교회에 더 많이 기부하세요."
What am I? Fund manager? Or a real estate investor?
나는 무엇입니까? 펀드매니저? 아니면 부동산 투자자?
Did you know?
알고 계셨나요?
Those decisions
그 결정
They are not for God or for me.
그것은 하나님을 위한 것도 아니고 나를 위한 것도 아닙니다.
Talk to Jun Kyung and Jun Seo.
준경, 서준과 대화하세요.
Yes. I see.
그렇습니다. 그렇군요.
You must be tired of hearing all this.
이 모든 것을 듣는 것에 지쳤을 것입니다.
- Congratulations! - You earned it.
- 축하해요! - 당신은 그것을 얻었습니다.
Do I deserve congratulations to get a job at this age?
나는 축하받을 자격이 있는가? 이 나이에 취업하려면?
Entering a public corporation is not easy.
공기업 입사가 쉽지 않네요.
Win the real estate lottery It's also difficult.
부동산 복권에 당첨되세요 그것은 또한 어렵습니다.
I never thought I'd have a day like this.
나에게 이런 날이 있을 줄은 꿈에도 몰랐다.
And you?
당신은요?
What's so special about being an adjunct?
보조원이 되면 어떤 특별한 점이 있나요?
It's keeping the students happy, see the humor of the teachers.
학생들을 행복하게 해주고 있어요. 선생님들의 유머를 보세요.
It sounds exhausting. You are doing your PhD and teaching.
피곤한 것 같습니다. 당신은 박사 학위를 취득하고 가르치고 있습니다.
Still, Professor Song takes care of you.
그래도 송 교수님이 챙겨주신다.
I'm always the weird one.
나는 항상 이상한 사람입니다.
One second.
1초.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
True, it is today.
사실, 오늘입니다.
Did you forget the anniversary of Mom's death?
엄마 기일을 잊으셨나요?
No, I didn't forget.
아니요, 잊지 않았습니다.
I knew it, really.
나는 그것을 정말로 알고 있었다.
It just happened to me.
방금 나에게 일어난 일입니다.
You forgot.
당신은 잊어버렸습니다.
Anyway, come home at six.
어쨌든 6시에 집에 오세요.
In fact,
사실,
I'm with friends. It's been a long time.
나는 친구들과 함께 있어요. 오랜만이에요.
And?
그리고?
OK that's fine.
알았어, 괜찮아.
I don't understand.
모르겠어요.
- Hello, Jun Kyung. - Hello.
- 안녕, 준경아. - 안녕하세요.
You look pretty today.
오늘 너 정말 예뻐 보이는구나.
The last time the expenditure was 50,000 won,
지난번 지출은 5만원이었는데,
and he only paid 30,000. I covered the rest.
그리고 그는 단지 30,000달러만 지불했습니다. 나머지는 다 가렸어요.
Hey, don't invite him next time.
다음부턴 그 사람 초대하지 마세요.
It's uncomfortable.
불편해요.
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
People can be out of money sometimes.
사람들은 때때로 돈이 부족할 수 있습니다.
That's fine when you're at school.
학교에 있을 때는 괜찮습니다.
Seriously,
진지하게,
Why are you a teaching assistant?
왜 조교인가요?
Do you want to be adjunct or something?
보조원인가 뭔가 하고 싶나요?
If you want to be a teacher,
선생님이 되고 싶다면,
He should have taken care of his notes.
그는 자신의 메모를 잘 관리했어야 했습니다.
He couldn't even graduate on time.
그는 제때 졸업하지도 못했습니다.
He does it because he doesn't know how to do anything else.
그는 다른 일을 할 줄 모르기 때문에 그렇게 합니다.
Have you ever tried to get a job?
당신은 취업을 시도한 적이 있습니까?
It doesn't even have a TOEIC score.
토익 점수도 없습니다.
Maybe he's just afraid.
어쩌면 그는 단지 두려워했을 수도 있습니다.
He knows well that he is nobody.
그는 자신이 아무 것도 아니라는 것을 잘 알고 있습니다.
I don't mind.
나는 상관하지 않는다.
Just tell him to pay his share.
그냥 그 사람에게 자기 몫을 지불하라고 하세요.
Don't talk like that behind his back,
그 사람 뒤에서 그런 말은 하지 마세요.
finish it.
끝내세요.
Your transaction is being processed.
귀하의 거래가 처리 중입니다.
[Cash withdrawal: 70,000 won Balance: 87,208 won]
[현금인출 : 70,000원 잔액 : 87,208원]
Hey, where did you go?
이봐요, 어디로 갔나요?
The food is cold, eat.
음식이 차가워요, 먹어요.
It's the 20,000 won I owed you last time.
지난번에 갚아야 할 2만원이에요.
and 50,000 won today.
그리고 오늘은 5만원.
Alright?
괜찮은?
That?
저것?
I asked if it's okay.
나는 괜찮은지 물었다.
Yes.
예.
Hey, your bag...
야, 네 가방...
You forgot your bag.
당신은 가방을 잊어버렸습니다.
Yun Ju!
윤주!
Hello.
안녕하세요.
So long!
그럼 또!
Look at this awkward hug.
이 어색한 포옹을 보세요.
What do you have to worry about?
무엇을 걱정해야 합니까?
A return recital after moving
이사 후 귀국 발표회
and everyone will fight to hire her as a teacher.
그리고 모두가 그녀를 고용하기 위해 싸울 것입니다 교사로서.
And if you get tired, you may simply not work.
그리고 피곤하면 일하지 않을 수도 있습니다.
I know.
알아요.
Worry about her It's the most useless thing in the world.
그녀에 대해 걱정 그것은 세상에서 가장 쓸모없는 일이다.
You should have stayed in Germany.
당신은 독일에 머물렀어야 했어요.
You're messing with the natural order here.
당신은 여기서 자연의 질서를 어지럽히고 있습니다.
- Don't exaggerate. - Exaggerate?
- 과장하지 마세요. - 과장?
Our environment is brutal these days. It's ruthless.
요즘 우리의 환경은 잔인합니다. 무자비합니다.
Yes.
예.
Of all of us, Do Hyun is the popular one.
우리 중 도현이가 인기가 많아요.
In fact, I wrote to him today to ask him if he would come.
사실 오늘 그 사람한테 편지를 썼어요 그가 올 것인지 물어보기 위해.
He said he couldn't, he's recording today.
못하겠다고 하셔서 오늘 녹음 중이거든요.
- Recording? - Yes.
- 녹음이요? - 예.
- A weekend?
- 주말요?
Wow,
와,
must be in high demand.
수요가 많아야 합니다.
Hey, Do Hyun and I dated freshman year.
안녕하세요 도현이랑 저는 1학년때 사귄 적이 있어요.
It was a long time ago, they can talk about it.
오래 전 일이므로 그것에 대해 이야기 할 수 있습니다.
Is that okay with you?
괜찮으세요?
I saw him a few days ago,
며칠 전에 그 사람을 봤는데,
we are very well.
우리는 아주 잘 지내요.
What is that relaxed energy?
그 여유로운 에너지는 무엇일까?
Are we in Hollywood or something?
우리는 헐리우드인가 뭔가에 있는 걸까?
Are you back to stay?
다시 머물러 오셨나요?
I thought about it a lot before coming back.
돌아오기 전에 많은 생각을 했어요.
But yes, I decided to live here.
하지만 네, 저는 여기서 살기로 결정했습니다.
Good for you.
당신에게 좋습니다.
It's disappointing,
실망스럽습니다.
but I understand.
하지만 이해해요.
My patients' water breaks from one moment to the next,
내 환자의 양수 중단 어느 순간부터 다음 순간까지,
Births are scheduled suddenly.
출산은 갑자기 예정되어 있습니다.
I also missed plans with you many times.
나도 너와의 계획을 여러번 놓쳤어.
Thank you for understanding.
이해해 주셔서 감사합니다.
Alright.
괜찮은.
Good luck with the recording.
녹음 잘 하시길 바랍니다.
- Come on. - Yes.
- 어서 해봐요. - 예.
He hadn't come for a long time.
그는 오랫동안 오지 않았습니다.
Sorry for leaving you with the kids. All weekend, darling.
아이들과 함께 떠나서 미안해요. 주말 내내, 얘야.
You know what advertisers are like. They change their minds all the time.
광고주가 어떤 사람인지 아시나요? 그들은 항상 마음을 바꿉니다.
Yes.
예.
It's okay, honey.
괜찮아, 얘야.
I'll try to finish as quickly as I can.
최대한 빨리 끝내도록 노력하겠습니다.
Okay, bye.
알았어, 안녕.
Look at you.
당신을보세요.
You were going to dress well
너 옷 잘 입으려고 했어
and go to the wedding with your girlfriend,
그리고 여자친구랑 결혼식에 가세요.
but the agenda exploded, right?
그런데 의제가 터졌죠?
Because?
왜냐하면?
you and your wife
당신과 당신의 아내
they were so anxious
그들은 너무 불안해했어요
like Jun Kyung and me.
나와 준경이처럼.
And how
그리고 어떻게
did they get married?
그 사람들 결혼했어요?
Yes, we were afraid.
그래요, 우리는 두려웠어요.
There were many crises,
위기도 많았고,
but honestly,
하지만 솔직히,
when I got married,
내가 결혼했을 때,
All that anxiety disappeared.
그 불안함은 모두 사라졌습니다.
Sounds ridiculous, doesn't it?
말도 안되는 소리이지, 그렇지?
- Heavens. - What nonsense.
- 천국. - 말도 안 되는 소리야.
That hurts.
아프다.
If you remain considerate
계속 배려한다면
and worrying about the circumstances, you will never get married.
상황을 걱정하고, 당신은 결코 결혼하지 않을 것입니다.
You need a little selfishness,
약간의 이기심이 필요해요.
put yourself first.
자신을 먼저 생각하십시오.
That's the only way it works.
그것이 작동하는 유일한 방법입니다.
How can I be selfish in my situation?
내 상황에서 어떻게 이기적이 될 수 있습니까?
Because?
왜냐하면?
For Daniel?
다니엘에게?
See? You can't anymore.
보다? 더 이상 할 수 없습니다.
I don't even know how she feels.
나는 그녀가 어떻게 느끼는지조차 모릅니다.
Oh,
오,
you are very arrogant.
당신은 매우 거만합니다.
How do you expect to know What does someone feel without trying?
어떻게 알 수 있을 것 같나요? 누군가가 시도하지 않고 느끼는 것은 무엇입니까?
If you want to know how it feels, ask him the question.
어떤 느낌인지 알고 싶다면, 그에게 질문을 해보세요.
That way you will know for sure.
그래야 확실히 알 수 있습니다.
That giraffe, Dr. Yeom,
저 기린 염박사님
stretched out those long arms
그 긴 팔을 뻗어
and lifted him up,
그리고 그를 들어올렸다.
and somehow it flew and landed right in your arms.
그리고 어떻게든 날아갔지 그리고 바로 당신의 품에 안착했습니다.
It's destiny.
그것은 운명이다.
So,
그래서,
when will they do it?
그 사람들은 언제 할 거야?
That?
저것?
Get married?
결혼?
We haven't even talked about that.
우리는 그것에 대해 이야기조차 하지 않았습니다.
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
Blink once and you'll have 40.
한 번 깜박이면 40개가 됩니다.
How come they have never talked about marriage?
왜 그들은 결혼에 대해 한 번도 이야기한 적이 없나요?
Why do we need something so expensive and formal
왜 그렇게 비싸고 공식적인 것이 필요한가요?
that only causes problems for everyone?
그건 모두에게 문제만 야기하는 건가요?
Do Hyun and I are fine like this.
나와 도현은 이대로도 괜찮다.
That's enough for us.
우리에게는 그것으로 충분합니다.
But I don't think being well is enough.
하지만 나는 건강해지는 것만으로는 충분하지 않다고 생각합니다.
Oh.
오.
Jun Kyung?
준경?
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Oh.
오.
So, there was a recording.
그래서 녹음이 있었죠.
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
I thought he lied about the recording
난 그가 녹음에 대해 거짓말을 한 줄 알았는데
just to go out with you.
그냥 너랑 데이트하려고.
It's a joke.
농담이에요.
You look like you're coming from a wedding.
당신은 결혼식에서 오는 것처럼 보입니다.
They say that if you don't get married six months after catching him,
결혼 안 하면 된다고 하던데 그를 잡은 지 6개월 만에
You can't for three years.
3년 동안은 할 수 없습니다.
That's a joke too.
그것도 농담이에요.
I guess we'll meet again, right?
우리 다시 만날 것 같아요, 그렇죠?
Oh.
오.
That really crosses the line.
정말 선을 넘는군요.
It doesn't filter anything,
아무것도 필터링하지 않습니다.
He just says what comes to mind.
그는 단지 생각나는 대로 말합니다.
It wasn't my fault I got angry at that moment.
그 순간 화가 난 것은 내 잘못이 아니었습니다.
It was hers.
그것은 그녀의 것이었습니다.
See?
보다?
Still not thinking about getting married?
아직도 결혼할 생각이 없나요?
A very strong rival has just appeared.
아주 강력한 라이벌이 나타났습니다.
Is that all you brought?
가져온 게 그게 다야?
Thanks to your mom,
엄마 덕분에,
We are all together again.
우리는 모두 다시 함께합니다.
It was spring then, but it was very cold.
그때는 봄이었는데, 하지만 매우 추웠어요.
This year feels warmer, right?
올해는 좀 더 따뜻해진 것 같죠?
Yes.
예.
Did something happen?
무슨 일이 있었나요?
That? Nothing.
저것? 아무것도 아님.
Yes, nothing happened.
예, 아무 일도 일어나지 않았습니다.
Do you want us to have a drink together?
우리 같이 한잔 할래요?
We haven't done it in a while.
우리는 그것을 한동안 하지 않았습니다.
Let's drink.
마시자.
Alright.
괜찮은.
You're not drinking, are you?
너 술 안 마시는구나, 그렇지?
- I'll just hold the glass. - You came by car, right?
- 잔만 들고 있을게요. - 차로 오셨죠?
- Yes. - Okay.
- 예. - 좋아요.
Take.
가져가다.
Dad, is something wrong?
아빠, 무슨 일이라도 있으신가요?
I've been thinking
나는 생각해왔다
If I should say this today,
오늘 이 말을 하자면,
but both have been busy.
하지만 둘 다 바빴어요.
And since we're all together now...
그리고 이제 우리는 모두 함께 있으니까...
I think it's time.
이제 때가 된 것 같아요.
Do you two
둘이서 해?
will they get married?
그 사람들 결혼할까?
That?
저것?
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
Will they really get married?
그들은 정말로 결혼할 것인가?
No, I'm too old to get married.
아니요, 결혼하기엔 너무 늙었어요.
It's not that.
그게 아닙니다.
I'm thinking
나는 생각하고있다
to sell this house.
이 집을 팔려고요.
Will you sell the house?
집을 팔 것인가?
Does that make sense?
그게 말이 되나요?
That's why dad wanted to talk about it.
그래서 아빠는 그것에 대해 이야기하고 싶었습니다.
I object.
나는 반대한다.
And you?
당신은요?
Dad wants to sell the house
아빠가 집을 팔고 싶어해요
to set up camp with that woman.
그 여자와 캠프를 세우려고요.
This is the house where mom lived with all of us.
이 집이다 엄마가 우리 모두와 함께 살았던 곳.
Is that okay with you?
괜찮으세요?
Yeah?
응?
I asked you if that's okay with you.
나는 당신에게 괜찮은지 물었습니다.
This is dad's house.
이곳은 아빠 집이에요.
You have the right to decide.
귀하에게는 결정할 권리가 있습니다.
but
하지만
It seems sudden.
갑작스러운 것 같습니다.
How is this dad's house? It's our house.
이 아빠 집은 어떤가요? 우리 집이에요.
No?
아니요?
So where will we go?
그럼 어디로 갈까요?
Will we meet as a family at barbecue places?
우리는 가족으로 만날 것인가 바비큐 장소에서?
Stop exaggerating
과장하지 마세요
He's just thinking about it.
그는 단지 그것에 대해 생각하고 있습니다.
Just thinking about it is crazy!
생각만 해도 미친 짓이다!
How could you, dad?
어떻게 그럴 수 있어요, 아빠?
This is the only home I have ever stayed in.
이 집은 내가 머물렀던 유일한 집이다.
I was born here, I've lived here my whole life.
나는 여기서 태어났고 평생을 여기서 살았습니다.
How can you do this to me?
어떻게 나한테 이럴 수가 있어?
Obviously I'll get you a place to live.
분명히 내가 당신에게 살 곳을 마련해줄 거예요.
Clear.
분명한.
So I'm the problem.
그러니까 내가 문제야.
I'm the only one with no future or anywhere to go,
나에겐 미래도 없고 갈 곳도 없는 유일한 사람이다.
so while I'm gone, you can sell the house.
그래서 내가 없는 동안 집을 팔 수 있어요.
It's not like that.
그렇지 않습니다.
Am I not family?
나는 가족이 아닌가?
- Am I just luggage? - Hey.
- 그냥 짐인가요? - 여기요.
Today is the anniversary of Mom's death.
오늘은 엄마의 기일이다.
How could you...?
어떻게 그럴 수가...?
This wasn't even my room,
여긴 내 방도 아니었는데,
It was dad's house, dad's room.
아빠의 집, 아빠의 방이었습니다.
Sorry, I've lived here for 29 years.
죄송합니다. 저는 여기서 29년 동안 살았습니다.
Enough!
충분한!
I don't need a studio,
스튜디오는 필요없어요
I don't need your money.
나는 당신의 돈이 필요하지 않습니다.
You and that woman will live happily ever after.
당신과 그 여자는 오래오래 행복하게 살 거예요.
A camp?
캠프?
It sounds fun.
재미있을 것 같네요.
Yes, I will be happy with her,
응, 난 그녀와 함께 있으면 행복할 거야
we will live well!
우리 잘 살게요!
Now go!
이제 가세요!
How are you going to survive?
어떻게 살아남을 건가요?
You have no money or skills.
돈도 없고 기술도 없습니다.
Nothing!
아무것도 아님!
Will you live off your sister again?
또 누나한테 의지해서 살 거야?
Is that the plan?
그게 계획인가요?
Get out!
나가세요!
Well, I mean...
글쎄, 내 말은...
Jun Seo.
서준.
Jun Seo!
서준!
What did I do so wrong?
내가 뭘 그렇게 잘못했지?
I worked until I was tired,
피곤할 때까지 일했는데,
I bought this house,
나는 이 집을 샀고,
and now I want to sell it...
이제 팔고 싶은데...
and find my own happiness.
그리고 나만의 행복을 찾아보세요.
Is that a crime?
그게 범죄인가요?
I don't know well.
잘 모르겠어요.
Leave.
떠나다.
There were four of us in that house.
그 집에는 우리 4명이 있었습니다.
One day, suddenly we became three...
어느날 갑자기 우리는 셋이 되었다...
then in two...
그럼 2번에...
and now, there was only one left.
이제 이제 하나만 남았습니다.
Can we still...
아직도...
call it family...
가족이라고 부르세요...
even if there is only one left?
한 개만 남더라도?
The number you dialed is not available.
당신이 전화한 번호는 사용할 수 없는 번호입니다.
[Phone call]
[전화통화]
[My son]
[내 아들]
[My dad]
[우리 아빠]
Are you really not going to answer?
정말 대답 안 할 거야?
What could I say?
내가 뭐라고 말할 수 있니?
I didn't do anything wrong.
나는 아무 잘못도 하지 않았습니다.
I didn't say anything bad.
나는 나쁜 말을하지 않았습니다.
Dad will say he's sorry again.
아빠는 또 미안하다고 말씀하실 거예요.
And now I don't want to say I'm fine.
그리고 지금은 괜찮다고 말하고 싶지 않아요.
Everyone supported me...
다들 응원해줬는데...
even if it was a burden and a nuisance.
비록 그것이 부담이고 귀찮은 일이라 할지라도.
Everyone knew it...
다들 알고 있었지...
and I was the only one who didn't know.
그리고 나는 몰랐던 유일한 사람이었습니다.
Like an idiot...
바보처럼...
I'm the last one to notice.
나는 마지막으로 눈치 채는 사람이다.
When I was little,
내가 어렸을 때,
people always called you "Jun Kyung's mom."
사람들은 항상 당신에게 전화했어요 "준경 엄마요."
Why didn't they ever call you? "Jun Seo's mom"?
왜 그들은 당신에게 전화하지 않았나요? "서준 엄마"?
I thought
나는 생각했다
which was because Jun Kyung had been born first.
준경이 먼저 태어났기 때문이다.
but everyone knew
하지만 다들 알고 있었어
that he was smart and did well in school
그 사람 똑똑하고 학교 공부도 잘했다고
and that I was the stupid one.
그리고 내가 바보였다고.
The useless one.
쓸모없는 것.
Were you ashamed of me too, mom?
엄마도 제가 부끄러웠나요?
Why would I do it?
내가 왜 그럴까요?
You are the most beautiful thing in the world
당신은 세상에서 가장 아름다운 것입니다
for me.
나를 위해.
You are what makes me most proud.
당신은 나를 가장 자랑스럽게 만드는 사람입니다.
Don't say that.
그렇게 말하지 마세요.
That's why I hate you more than anyone.
그래서 나는 누구보다 당신을 싫어합니다.
You should have scolded me sometimes.
가끔은 나를 꾸짖었어야 했는데.
You always said it was good, and that's why I ended up like this.
늘 좋다고 하셨는데, 그래서 내가 이렇게 된 거야.
Do you know how I feel?
내 기분이 어떤지 알아?
How could I not know?
내가 어떻게 모를 수 있겠는가?
You don't know how to hide
넌 숨기는 법을 모르잖아
your feelings.
당신의 감정.
What are you doing here?
여기서 뭐하는거야?
The field has been closed for a long time.
해당 필드는 오랫동안 폐쇄되었습니다.
Go away.
저리 가요.
Lord...
주님...
I have nowhere to go.
나는 갈 곳이 없다.
That?
저것?
Go away.
저리 가요.
Hello, Daniel.
안녕, 다니엘.
What's happening at this time?
지금 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는 걸까요?
Wait a second.
잠깐만요.
It's me, Im Yun Ju.
나 임윤주입니다.
I've been thinking about what happened today.
오늘 무슨 일이 일어났는지 생각해 봤습니다.
It seems that you misunderstood a harmless joke.
오해하신 것 같습니다. 무해한 농담입니다.
Are we close enough to joke like that?
우리는 그런 농담을 할 만큼 친합니까?
That's why I called you, I wanted to apologize.
그래서 전화해서 사과하고 싶었어요.
Is this an apology I should accept?
이것이 내가 받아들여야 할 사과인가?
If you do not accept it,
수락하지 않을 경우
I can't do anything.
나는 아무것도 할 수 없습니다.
It looks like you're driving, I'm going to hang up.
운전 중이신 것 같으니 전화를 끊겠습니다.
What's wrong with him?
그 사람에게 무슨 문제가 있습니까?
Hey!
여기요!
Roll down the window!
창문을 내려라!
I said put it down!
내려놓으라고 했어!
The traffic light changed centuries ago. Why are you still standing?
신호등은 수세기 전에 바뀌었습니다. 왜 아직도 서 있나요?
Crazy bitch.
미친년아.
That?
저것?
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
Drive better next time.
다음에는 더 잘 운전하세요.
Hey.
여기요.
You call that an apology?
그걸 사과라고 부르나요?
Do you pretend to be nice
착한 척 하는 거야?
just to feel better?
그냥 기분이 좋아지려고?
If you're going to apologize, do it well. If not, don't bother.
사과할 거면 잘 하세요. 그렇지 않다면 귀찮게하지 마십시오.
And stop smiling, you only make it worse.
그리고 웃지 마세요. 상황을 더 악화시킬 뿐입니다.
What the hell...?
도대체 무슨 일이야...?
Honey, come on.
여보, 어서요.
- Fast. - OK.
- 빠른. - 좋아요.
They are crazy.
그들은 미쳤다.
This woman bumped into us on purpose!
이 여자는 일부러 우리한테 부딪혔어요!
Well, wait a moment.
자, 잠깐만요.
You keep saying "wait."
당신은 계속 "잠깐만"이라고 말해요.
It takes forever, damn.
영원히 걸리잖아, 젠장.
Sir, please stop cursing.
선생님, 욕 좀 그만하세요.
This was not intentional.
이것은 의도적인 것이 아니었습니다.
That? How was it not intentional?
저것? 어떻게 의도하지 않았나요?
He blocked his lane on purpose.
그는 고의로 차선을 막았습니다.
You can see it here.
여기에서 볼 수 있습니다.
- How was I going to avoid that? - No, she...
- 그걸 어떻게 피할 수 있었나요? - 아니, 그 사람은...
He didn't move when the light changed.
신호등이 바뀌어도 그는 움직이지 않았습니다.
I was in a hurry.
나는 서두르고 있었다.
When in a hurry, Does he insult and drive aggressively?
급할 때, 그는 모욕하고 공격적으로 운전합니까?
No! This woman...
아니요! 이 여자...
Okay, let's stop.
알았어, 그만하자.
If you're going to fine us, do it quickly,
우리한테 벌금을 물릴 거면 빨리 해주세요.
Or let the insurance take care of it.
아니면 보험사에서 처리하도록 하세요.
Talking to her is useless.
그녀와 이야기하는 것은 쓸모가 없습니다.
This can't be handled with a fine or insurance.
이건 처리할 수 없어 벌금이나 보험으로.
Threatening driving It's not a traffic violation.
위협적인 운전 교통 위반이 아닙니다.
It is criminal intimidation according to the Penal Code.
형법상 협박죄에 해당합니다.
Curse.
저주.
After a hard day with only difficult people,
힘든 사람들과 힘든 하루를 보낸 뒤,
you end up meeting someone that gives you comfort.
당신은 결국 누군가를 만나게 됩니다 그것이 당신에게 편안함을 줍니다.
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
I was just happy to see you.
나는 단지 당신을 만나서 기뻤습니다.
So you work around here.
그래서 당신은 여기서 일합니다.
How strange to meet like this.
이렇게 만나다니 참 이상하네요.
My dad lives nearby, he was just passing by.
저희 아버지가 근처에 사시는데 그냥 지나가시더라구요.
So your name is Won Young.
그럼 이름은 원영이군요.
I knew the uniform looked good on you.
나는 그 유니폼이 당신에게 잘 어울린다는 것을 알고 있었습니다.
How unexpected.
정말 예상치 못한 일입니다.
I thought you were just a tough local
난 당신이 그냥 터프한 동네 사람인줄 알았는데
who liked to drink alone,
혼자 술 마시는 걸 좋아하는 사람,
but you are an obstetrician and gynecologist.
하지만 당신은 산부인과 전문의입니다.
You have changed a lot,
많이 변하셨네요,
in a good way.
좋은 방법으로.
You are the same.
당신도 똑같습니다.
You are still bold and cool.
당신은 여전히 ​​대담하고 멋있습니다.
Officer Oh.
오 장교.
If the station contacts you,
방송국에서 연락이 오면
You will have to come to testify.
당신은 증언하러 와야 할 것입니다.
OK.
좋아요.
Do you mind if I contact you again?
다시 연락드려도 될까요?
Of course not.
물론 그렇지 않습니다.
I'll buy beer next time.
다음에는 맥주를 사야겠습니다.
Sounds good.
좋은 것 같아요.
Next time, I'll call you friend.
다음에는 친구라고 부를게요.
OK.
좋아요.
Who was it?
누구였나요?
A friend.
친구.
A friend?
친구?
He looked a little older than you.
그 사람은 당신보다 조금 더 나이 들어 보여요.
It's someone who accompanied me when I was tired and alone.
같이 간 사람이에요 피곤하고 혼자였을 때.
So yeah, she's a friend. to which I am grateful.
그래, 그 사람은 친구야. 나는 감사하고 있습니다.
Great, thanks.
좋습니다. 감사합니다.
- Good job! - You did very well.
- 잘했어요! - 아주 잘했어요.
- You too. - Go home and rest.
- 너도. - 집에 가서 쉬세요.
Thanks for your effort.
노력해 주셔서 감사합니다.
Daniel.
다니엘.
Sorry, I'm late.
미안해요, 늦었어요.
I brought your pizza...
피자 가져왔어...
Good night, dad.
잘 자요, 아빠.
Excellent.
훌륭한.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Why are you always surprised when you see me?
왜 나를 보면 늘 놀라는 걸까?
Did I come to a place where I shouldn't?
내가 가지 말아야 할 곳에 온 걸까?
We already ate pizza,
우리는 이미 피자를 먹었고,
mom brought her.
엄마가 데려왔어.
I won!
내가 이겼어!
I couldn't even eat well,
밥도 잘 못 먹었는데,
but he still fed the fish.
하지만 그는 여전히 물고기에게 먹이를 주었습니다.
He must be very close friends with Jun Kyung,
그 사람 준경이랑 엄청 친할 것 같은데,
It makes me a little envious.
조금 부러워요.
Yun Ju.
윤주.
Yeah?
응?
That? Uncomfortable again?
저것? 또 불편해?
Do you feel uncomfortable?
불편함을 느끼시나요?
You're curious, right?
궁금하지 않나요?
You want to know why I came back to Korea.
내가 왜 한국에 왔는지 알고 싶나요?
Yes.
예.
For Daniel, I suppose.
다니엘에게는 그런 것 같아요.
Hey.
여기요.
Am I really that uncomfortable for you?
내가 정말 그렇게 불편한가요?
Do you really think I spent my time in Germany
내가 정말 독일에서 시간을 보냈다고 생각하시나요?
just thinking about you
너만 생각하고 있어
and missing you?
그리고 당신이 그리워요?
I dated people who liked me.
나는 나를 좋아하는 사람들과 데이트했습니다.
The work was going well,
일은 잘 진행되고 있었고,
and he was having a good time.
그는 즐거운 시간을 보내고 있었습니다.
Yes,
네,
I imagined it.
나는 그것을 상상했다.
But, Do Hyun...
그런데 도현아...
no matter how much I thought about it...
아무리 생각해도...
I always came back to you.
나는 항상 당신에게 돌아 왔습니다.
I came back for you.
나는 당신을 위해 돌아 왔습니다.
I want to try again with you.
나는 당신과 함께 다시 시도하고 싶습니다.
This time I will manage alone.
이번에는 혼자 관리하겠습니다.
Why?
왜?
To take revenge for the humiliation from my dad and my sister.
치욕에 대한 복수를 위해 아버지와 여동생에게서요.
Don't tell my dad, please.
아빠에게 말하지 마세요.
Never tell him.
절대 그 사람에게 말하지 마세요.
Come here...
여기로 오세요...
Do you think we're rushing?
우리가 서두르고 있다고 생각하시나요?
Jin Ho.
진호.
Are you still upset?
아직도 화났나요?
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
I think I was a little sensitive.
제가 좀 예민했던 것 같아요.
Ha Yeong!
하영!
When I was playing before, It brought back old memories.
예전에 게임을 할 때, 옛 추억을 되새겼습니다.
Me too.
저도요.
Do Hyun is still Daniel's dad.
도현은 여전히 다니엘의 아빠입니다.
Parents and children They can't choose each other,
부모와 자녀 그들은 서로를 선택할 수 없습니다.
and they can't be strangers either.
그리고 그들은 낯선 사람일 수도 없습니다.
What are you trying to say?
무슨 말을 하려는 건가요?
If you were me, what would you do?
당신이 나라면 어떻게 하시겠습니까?
Wouldn't you want to break it?
부수고 싶지 않으신가요?